- Previously on Gotham...
- On the count of three,
instead of telling me who you love,
- tell me who to kill.
- Kill Lee.
You chose Lee because you love Vale.
If a person comes into
contact with my blood,
it changes them.
Listen to me! I would never
do anything to hurt you.
Kristen.
No!
You wanted to save Lee.
You knew he would do the opposite.
You love Lee, which means we're done.
I have found someone. I have no choice
- but to confess my feelings to Ed.
- Da.
Is this about the test they're
running on Alice Tetch's blood?
Yes. The rats were exhibiting
manic tendencies...
- Violent rage.
- I assume they're, uh,
working on a cure.
Yes, but it could take years.
Nobody move!
What is going on?
I'm afraid your evening
has been hijacked.
Glasses down!
Is that my dear sister I see?
She's in you, isn't she?
- Miss Kringle?
- No, my name's Isabella.
You remind me of someone
that I used to know.
I met someone.
I think I'm in love.
I want to rejoin the GCPD.
Welcome back, Detective.
GCPD! Hands in the air!
Back away, slowly.
This ain't what it looks like.
Explain it to me down at the precinct.
For now, you'd be wise
to keep your mouth shu...
Listen, uh, can we talk about this?
Be reasonable, man.
Look, I didn't kill anybody, okay?
I'm the cleaner, that's it.
You're just the cleaner.
Yeah.
You're just the guy
who chops up the bodies
and dumps them in a vat of acid.
That's it.
What are you doing, man?
Just... take me in, okay?
Oh, I'll bet that's what you want.
For me to read you your rights,
make sure you get a lawyer.
Two, three years from now,
I see you on some corner,
free as a bird.
Any other night, yeah.
It would eat at me,
but, yeah, I'd do it.
Not tonight.
The Toad.
He-he's the one you
want. He gave me the job.
See, something's gotten into me.
When I see a scumbag like you,
my blood starts boiling in my veins.
I just want to punish
you, make you suffer.
Up until now, I've been
able to control it.
But it's getting stronger inside of me.
Please.
The Toad, I told you.
He's the one.
Just arrest me.
Arrest me!
We're past that.
Please!
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Morning.
We knew what we were
getting into, right?
When we agreed to let my dad
throw us an engagement party?
Oh, we knew.
I mean, who are these people?
He's very proud of you.
And he wants all of Gotham to know that.
Well, he succeeded, 'cause
he invited most of the city.
How are you so okay with this?
Because I agree with him.
He should be proud. As am I.
How did I get so lucky?
What is it?
James Gordon is returning to the GCPD.
- When?
- He starts today.
Um... how long have you known this?
A few days.
I'm sorry, I should
have told you sooner.
It's fine.
Is it?
I don't know, Lee.
We agreed he wouldn't
be part of our lives.
A-And now you're gonna
be working with him?
That's a part of our lives.
Do you trust me?
Because if you do,
then nothing else matters.
Of course I trust you.
And you're right, you're right,
it's all gonna be okay. It's just...
when I think about what
happened with Tetch,
a-and the things that Gordon said, I...
So, don't think about it.
I'll try.
But if you accidentally shot him...
I'd be okay with that, too.
No promises.
See you tonight.
Yeah.
Lock this bum up.
Hey, hey, hey!
There you are.
We got a call. Warehouse
district. You coming?
That's it? No "welcome back"?
Please. If we had a big to-do
every time you came back
to the GCPD, we'd never
catch any bad guys.
Ándale, partner.
Oh, and, uh,
I believe this...
belongs to you.
You coming or what?
Yeah, I'm coming.
What must be broken
before it can be used?
Eggs.
Correct! As always.
Oh, Edward, you spoil me.
You make it easy.
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm only gone two days.
Well, actually, your conference
ends at 1:45 on Monday.
With traffic, that puts
you in at 5:30 into Gotham.
If you leave on time today,
which I'm sure that you will... Mm-hmm.
You'll be gone for 44
and one half hours.
Less than two days.
I will hold on to that thought.
Cream! I forgot your cream.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
So what does one do at a
librarian's conference?
It would bore you.
Nothing that you would say,
do or think could bore me.
In that case, let me
read you my schedule.
Ooh!
Where did those glasses come from?
These?
These are my backup pair.
I normally wear contacts.
I thought you knew that.
Something wrong?
Edward, what is it?
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Excuse me.
It's just a pair of glasses.
I remember you loved that style on me.
Oh, dear.
I haven't upset you, have I, Ed?
I would've thought you
would've been used to
seeing people in mirrors.
You're just in my head.
Like that makes a difference.
But honestly, besides the fact
that she looks just like me,
you went from someone who files
papers in a police station
to someone who files books in a library.
Not super original.
You and Isabella are...
you're somewhat different.
Well, I'm dead.
And she's alive.
But how long will that last?
Until you...
I...
I would never hurt Isabella.
Bet you would've said
the same thing about me.
Face it, Ed.
You're a killer.
It's only a matter of time before...
Okay, so, a uni I.D.'d the vic.
One Paulie Penopolus,
aka Paulie Pennies.
Cleanup guy for the Gotham underworld.
Bingo. I'm thinking it was
some kind of business deal.
Maybe an unhappy customer.
Perhaps a competitor.
Good place to start.
Hey, listen, seriously, Jim...
I'm glad you're back.
Me too, Harv.
Feels good.
This wasn't just business.
We should call Barnes.
You know why I'm here.
Oh, yes.
Yes, indeed.
She's in there, isn't she?
Inside of you.
Hello, sister dear.
Just tell me.
You grew up with your sister.
You've seen this virus firsthand.
How do I beat it?
Hmm.
I believe
the way this works is...
you give me something,
I give you something.
Ticktock.
How's about I let you keep your teeth?!
Or...
my sister's virus
is a beautiful thing.
It makes the darkest
parts of a person sing.
What darkness in you...
has Alice brought to life?
Tell me that,
and I'll tell you everything I know.
Criminals.
The guilty.
My anger at them.
Oh, but it's not anger I see.
Rage.
Violent, bloody
rage.
All right, Tetch, my turn.
Is there a cure?
Yes.
There is a cure.
What is it?
You give in,
and let my dear sister win!
You think I'm playing?!
Have you heard the voices?
What voices?
The virus, even as it grows
stronger, waxes and wanes.
You may have the illusion
you're winning.
Then you hear the voices.
Those dark voices from deep within you,
whispering... whispering...
and finally,
you'll see the world as it really is.
Then there will be no
more Captain Barnes,
only Alice.
My dear Alice.
You don't know me!
You've dirtied your hands, haven't you?
And now you're desperately
trying to make it right.
I can make it right.
You're back.
I'm back.
I suppose it was only a matter of time.
Once a cop, always a cop.
For better or worse,
this is where I belong.
- How's Vale?
- Good. I think.
She's out of the hospital, anyway.
- You two are not...?
- No.
I'm not trying to make this awkward.
Why would it be? We're both adults.
There's no reason we
can't work together.
I'm glad you feel that way.
Mario agrees?
He will. Eventually.
Right.
Our engagement party is tonight.
I only bring it up because
a few people here are going.
Now it's awkward, isn't it?
A little.
You want to know about the two bodies
that, uh, were found this morning.
Yes.
I've only done the
preliminary examination,
but the John Doe in the acid,
his face had been removed.
Removed? How?
Scalpel? Razor blade?
Whoever did it knew exactly
what they were doing.
I'll have more for you soon.
Jim.
I think you made the right
decision coming back.
I know this doesn't exactly look like
"just business," but
right now we're thinking
whoever paid Paulie Pennies
to dispose of the body
in the bathtub, also
might have killed him
to tie up some loose ends.
Uh-huh.
Jim. Good to see you
with a shield again.
And a tie.
Captain, good to be back.
Bullock was just filling me in.
Hell of one to catch on your first day.
Yeah.
That's the preliminary report from Lee.
John Doe had his face removed.
- Trying to cover up his identity?
- Yeah, maybe.
But the acid would
have done that anyway.
I'm running point on this one.
- That's cool.
- Honestly, Cap...
Look, I know I've been away...
Maybe that's why
you've forgotten how
things go around here.
I give you an order and you follow it.
Which, for the record,
Captain, I totally support.
I'm taking point on this,
not giving you the day off.
Follow the physical evidence, Bullock.
Report back to me.
Aye, aye.
Jim.
I didn't mean to bite your head off.
It's just, sometimes the
ugliness here gets to me.
No need to explain.
Let me know if you need anything.
And, uh...
don't let the bastards
haze you too hard, rookie.
Yes, sir.
Gordon.
Here's the one you wanted, Captain.
Uh, mid-level felon, goes by "The Toad."
Yeah, that's him. Thank you.
Maybe she's right.
What if there's something
about Miss Kringle's...
Kristen's... Isabella's face?
What if there's something
about her face that
unlocks this side of me?
What if I do hurt her?
Oswald.
- Yes?
- You're smiling.
- I was?
- Yes.
Oh.
Well, I was just thinking...
how darned lucky Isabella is.
You love her, yet to protect her,
you are willing to break up with her.
Beautiful.
Sad, but beautiful.
So you think I should break up with her?
I'm sorry, I thought that's
what we were talking about.
Certainly, I would never pressure...
No, you're right.
If I did hurt her, I would
never forgive myself.
That life would put
her in your path again,
only to snatch her from you. Why?
I can't do it.
- What?
- I can't break up with her.
But you said yourself...
I need you to do it for me.
Would you do that?
I would be forever in your debt.
Just be gentle.
Of course.
I'm looking for a punk who supposedly
frequents this rat hole.
Goes by "The Toad."
Who's askin'?
Captain Nathaniel Barnes of the GCPD.
How about you and I go
down to the precinct,
and you can answer some questions?
Blow, pig.
I want to know about Paulie Pennies!
The body he was getting
rid of last night...
Where did it come from?!
Maybe you want me to
open that mouth for you.
Okay, stop.
I-I hired Paulie.
But I'm just a go-between.
I'm so sick of hearing that.
No one's responsible for anything.
Everyone's a middleman.
I want a name!
Symon, okay? Dr. Symon.
He's a big-time plastic surgeon.
So what, he likes cutting
people's faces off for kicks?
- Try again!
- No.
He's got a side business.
You get in trouble, you need a new face,
he gives you one.
A new face?
- Whose?
- I don't know.
I just get rid of the
bodies, that's all.
You think
you're not guilty,
but you are.
Stop, okay, stop!
It's Symon!
He's the one you want.
You're a cop.
Symon, huh?
Take me to him.
Mayor Cobblepot?
Hello, Isabella. May I?
Um, of course.
Going somewhere?
Just for a couple nights.
But I was hoping to talk
to Ed before I left.
Um, tried calling him. Is he okay?
Hmm. Yes.
How shall I put this?
It's over.
Excuse me?
He is not going to see you anymore.
Do not try to contact him.
That door is closed.
Have a nice life.
Oh, my.
It is a shock.
But besides your...
odd resemblance to his ex...
a certain facility with riddles...
compulsion for order...
what is it that you two
really have in common?
Edward is a person of
exceptional intelligence
and imagination.
He deserves to be appreciated
by someone on his own level.
And you,
my dear, are simply not.
Best to end things now.
You're right.
I don't deserve him.
Glad we agree.
Bye.
But I'm not gonna let him go.
He loves me. And I love him.
Do you know how rare that is, Mr. Mayor?
Of course you do.
Because you love him, too.
I can see it.
I'm not even jealous.
I-I don't think that you understand...
It was my glasses this morning.
They reminded him of Miss Kringle.
He's afraid he's going to
hurt me like he hurt her.
Listen to me, you little idiot,
I am telling you one last time,
- let... Ed... go.
- No.
I will write to him.
I will make him understand
he has nothing to fear.
I'm not gonna let him go.
Very well.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
You better not have been lying to me.
I'm not. This is his place.
You're not gonna kill me, are you?
I'm trying.
I'm about to take the face.
Be here in an hour, and
we can do the transplant.
You haven't eaten today, have you?
Very good.
I have to thank you, my dear,
for taking such care of your skin.
Excellent elasticity.
Now hold still.
Who's there?!
Quiet. Or we'll forgo any anesthesia.
I said, who's there?
GCPD.
You're under arrest.
Go for it.
Please.
I surrender.
Ma'am, you all right?
How many?
Excuse me?
How many have you killed?!
How many faces have you taken?
I have the right to an attorney.
I wish to invoke
that right... now.
Guilty.Guilty.
Who's there?! Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
No one. It's only me.
Guilty. He's guilty! Guilty.
- Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
- What is wrong with you?
He's guilty. Guilty.
What are you doing?
Arrest me.
Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
- I'm not resisting!
- Guilty!
Guilty! Guilty! Guilty!
Guilty. He's guilty.
Guilty.
The point Dr. Thompkins hopes you pay
particular attention to is
the level of strength required
to sever Paulie Pennie"
head from his torso.
And what level would that be, Lucius?
Extreme.
Extreme strength. Got it.
As for the other victim in the
bathtub, we haven't gotten any hits
on his prints, but a puncture
mark in his arm suggests
he was drugged prior to
having his face removed.
I'll run toxicology, I'll let
you know what I come up with.
Thanks, Lucius.
Yep.
It's good to have you back, Gordon.
Lucius, you're in
forensics, not the M.E.
Is there a reason Lee
didn't bring this herself?
Dr. Thompkins has
already gone for the day.
Her engagement party.
Right.
I hear it's gonna be quite the affair.
Beautiful women,
free booze, canapés.
- Harvey, you can go if you want.
- Oh, no.
I'd much rather spend time
here with my old partner.
Much more fun.
Besides,
I wasn't invited.
Captain!
Bullock, book this
piece of human garbage
for the murder of John Doe.
You got it, Captain. Come on.
Plastic surgeon.
Face man for the underworld.
He had a girl on the table.
If I had been there
five minutes later...
But you weren't.
You did it, Captain.
Yeah.
Today.
You know that feeling, Jim,
when you've won the battle
but you know you're gonna lose the war?
Wars are fought one
battle at a time, sir.
You said he killed the John Doe?
- Not Paulie Pennies?
- No.
His killer's still out there.
I'll get him tomorrow.
Promise.
My father and I haven't
always seen eye to eye.
But I think, Dad, you'll agree that...
marrying Lee is the best
decision I've ever made.
Without a doubt.
And Lee.
You're a doctor, a member of our city's
police department.
You're funny, compassionate
and brilliant.
Despite insisting all dogs are boys
and all cats are girls...
it's hopeless, I've
tried to correct her...
I've loved you since
the moment I saw you.
So wonderful.
Lee.
Congrats.
You look gorgeous. No surprise.
- Barbara. How did you...
- Get in?
As a plus one. With that guy there.
Hey.
Or it might have been him.
You need to leave, right now.
Can't we bury the hatchet?
So I came at you with a knife,
kidnapped you, whatever.
I've forgiven you for
beating me unconscious.
Water under the bridge.
You just stay right here,
I'm gonna get someone.
I'm leaving.
Just wanted to ask.
As someone else who was
once with Jim Gordon,
don't you miss it?
Miss what?
The heat.
Being so close to so
much darkness and light,
to someone always at war with himself.
Let me think... Tormented Jim Gordon,
or Mario, who I know is a good man,
who'll be a wonderful
father to my children,
and whom I love.
No. I don't miss it.
Wow.
I think you actually believe that.
It's kind of sad.
Tell my dates I've left, would you?
Uh-uh.
Don't let her ruin your night.
Captain. I'm so glad you came.
I-I can't stay.
I came to congratulate you.
You deserve to be happy.
Thank you.
But you have to stay
for at least one drink.
If nothing else,
to save me from these people.
One drink.
- But no work talk.
- Deal.
So, among the materials
confiscated in Symon's lab,
I came across a unique
anesthetic cocktail.
Let me guess.
The same cocktail toxicology
found in the John Doe.
Exactly.
Hey. I got some bad news.
- Symon walked.
- What?
The girl he had tied up
refused to press charges.
They probably paid her off.
And we just got an
order from Judge Bam-Bam
demanding his immediate release.
The Botox son of a
bitch is uber-connected.
The toxicology definitely ties
Symon to the John Doe murder.
We got to get him back here.
Captain Barnes?
Carmine Falcone.
I don't believe we've met.
No.
But I was just leaving.
I see.
Is my company so odious?
You belong behind bars.
I'm retired.
After running Gotham's
underworld for 30 years.
This city was built
because of men like me.
People have jobs because of men like me.
That whiskey you're drinking?
Paid for through my work.
So you did some good. So what?
Doesn't mean you're above the law.
Nobody is.
You know, whenever I hear a man
possessed of such certainty,
I always think he's trying
mostly to convince himself.
I wish you a pleasant evening, Captain.
Hey, Captain.
Alvarez.
Tell Gordon I'm bringing
him the man responsible
for Paulie Pennies' murder.
No backup.
He's coming in of his own accord.
Sure thing, Captain.
But you should know, the
judge released Dr. Symon.
Captain?
Guilty.
Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty!
Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty! Guilty.
Guilty.
Isabella.
Isabella, I got your note.
I thought you needed to
leave for your conference.
I can be late, Edward.
This is more important.
Oswa...
Oswald...
the mayor, he informed me
of your position, um...
but believe me, I-I think...
our breaking up is for the best.
No, Edward, it's not.
I understand your fear. It
comes from a place of love.
I know you won't hurt me.
You never could.
I don't think that you...
Oh, my...
Kristen.
I found old photos in newspapers.
You have to... I need to leave now.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no. Look at me.
Look at me!
You don't know what you're doing.
I am forcing you to face your fear.
You won't hurt me, even
when I look like this.
Edward.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Edward.
Should I take the glasses off?
Keep them on.
Seal off the exits, but do it quietly.
Last thing anyone wants
- is a scene.
- Yes, sir.
Little late for that.
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry, but we have to make an arrest
in the Paulie Pennies
case. We tried to get
the guy at home, but his housekeeper
said he was here. Just makes you realize
what a small town Gotham is, doesn't it?
Couldn't you wait?
If he's here, he's not exactly running.
She makes a good point, Jim.
You want to take that one?
Good evening, everyone.
Jim. What's going on?
Apparently, there's a murder
suspect among our guests.
Can I ask who?
Dr. Maxwell Symon.
- He's a...
- Plastic surgeon.
You arrest him, you're
gonna have to fight off
every woman here.
He's a favorite.
He's also a murderer.
I'd be curious to know
how your father knows him.
I'm sure that their relationship
is completely above board.
While you two hash this out,
I'm gonna go grab Symon.
- Harvey.
- What? I can handle
a plastic surgeon on my own.
And don't worry,
discretion is my middle name.
Lee, I'd like a word with Jim.
- Mario...
- It'll be fine.
Okay.
Look, Mario, I have a job to do,
so whatever this is...
When you told Tetch to kill Lee,
you knew he would do the opposite.
You sacrificed your
girlfriend for my fiancée.
That's insane.
Can we just admit you still love her?
- I don't have time for this.
- Hey.
You once told me that
if I ever hurt Lee,
you'd kill me.
Well, now it's my turn.
I love Lee and I'll do
whatever I have to to keep her.
Then word of advice...
lose the jealousy.
It's weak.
Gordon.
For Lee, I'll give you that one.
Oh, Captain... if you
keep frowning like that,
you'll never get those
wrinkles out around your mouth.
Come down to my office tomorrow.
I'll give you a free evaluation.
I'm surprised you can feel that
through that thing you call a face.
What are you doing?!
What I should have done all along.
You're insane.
Oh, no, Doc.
I'm saner than I've ever been.
I'm seeing things clearly...
for the very first time.
All these years, I've put
my trust in the system,
my trust in the law, held myself back
from doing what I really wanted to do.
And then I saw the truth.
It's not just you that's guilty.
This whole city is guilty.
Stop.
You're a police officer, for God's sake!
You have to follow the law.
I don't have to do anything.
I am the law.
I am judge...
jury...
and executioner!
Ed.
- How'd she take it?
- What?
Oh. Uh, um... everything is...
wonderful.
Isabella showed me that, uh...
I was worried over nothing.
I'm so happy for you.
But... why are you back?
Well, she had to go to her conference.
I insisted.
You're a good man.
But you look done in.
I will hear all about it tomorrow.
Get some sleep.
Got to give her credit.
She fought for him.
Too bad she underestimated her opponent.
I'm assuming it's done.
Yup.
Feel kind of bad, though, boss.
I always liked librarians.
You?
What about poor Ed?
He will be heartbroken.
Luckily, he has a shoulder to cry on.
Uh-oh. Come on. No, no.
Oh, come on. Uh-oh.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Help me, help me! Somebody, help!
Oh, dear.
Jim, you and Mario
have a heart-to-heart?
- Yeah. Where's Symon?
- No luck.
He must have skedaddled.
I thought he might be at the bar.
Uh-huh. Okay.
Keep a perimeter in
case he shows back up.
I'm gonna head to his house.
And, Harvey, uh... take it easy, huh?
It's good to have you back again, Jim.
- Uh-huh.
- I'm real glad.
Captain.
- Did you hear?
- Everything.
I saw Symon here earlier.
You manage to pick him up?
Not yet. He must've skipped
out when we showed up.
We'll get him.
Alvarez said you were bringing in
the guy who did Paulie Pennies.
Turned out to be a dead end.
I'll let you know when I find Symon.
Jim.
Things are gonna change around here.
You and I are gonna make
a difference in this city.
We're gonna clean it up.
Yes, sir.
Guilty. Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty. Guilty.
Guilty!
Guilty! Guilty!
Guilty.
Guilty.Guilty.
GCPD. Sir?
Dr. Symon.
Who did this?
Barnes.
www.tvsubtitles.net